Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode. Subtitles will likely not function properly. Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv: https://mpv.io
Der benutzte Mediaplayer unterstützt das in dieser Episode verwendete Untertitelformat nicht. Die Untertitel werden wahrscheinlich nicht korrekt angezeigt werden. Bitte verwende einen der empfohlenen Videoplayer, vorzugsweise mpv: https://mpv.io
Wealth, fame, power...
Reichtum, Macht und Ruhm.
Gold Roger, the King of the Pirates, obtained everything the world has to offer.
Der Mann, der sich dies alles erkämpft hatte,
Soundtracking
Soundtracking
Halee
Halee
Quality Control
Quality Control
Feeso Galaxy 900 Pepperjack Sewil
Feeso Galaxy 900 Pepperjack Sewil
Feeso Galaxy 900 Pepperjack Sewil
Feeso Galaxy 900 Pepperjack Sewil
What he said in his final moments drove countless souls to the seas.
Als er hingerichtet wurde, waren seine letzten Worte:
Timing
„Ihr wollt meinen Schatz? Den könnt ihr haben! Sucht ihn doch!
Subtitle Editing
Subtitle Editing
Ravenfire themuffinman985 Zenef
dennisjagut
Everything is right where I left it!
Irgendwo hab ich den größten Schatz der Welt versteckt!“
People set their sights on the Grand Line in pursuit of their dreams.
Dieser Schatz ist das One Piece und er liegt irgendwo auf der Grand Line.
The world has truly entered the Great Pirate Era!
Damit brach das große Piratenzeitalter an!
We'
Wir
A
A
re go
fol
ri
ri
ing
gen
tta
tta
to
al
ke
ke
ga
le
no
no
th
un
yu
yu
er
se
me
me
up
ren
wo
wo
all
Träu
A
A
our
men.
ka
ka
dr
ki
ki
ri
ri
a
ea
tsu
a
tta
ms
me
tsu
ke
tta
no
yu
yu
me
me
wo
wo
ka
ka
ki
ki
a
a
tsu
tsu
me
me
We'
Wir
re go
fol
ing
gen
to
al
ga
le
th
un
er
se
up
ren
all
und
our
Sa
dr
Träu
and
zie
Sa
ga
ea
men.
set
hen
ga
shi
ms
hi
out
mo
shi
naus,
in
no
mo
um
se
wo
no
auf
ar
sa
wo
Schatz
ch
ga
sa
su
of
shi
ga
che
so
ni
shi
Sa
me
zu
ni
yu
Sa
ge
th
ku
yu
hen:
ing
no
ku
sa
to
ga
no
shi
fi
mo
shi
no
mo
wo
no
sa
sa
ga
ga
shi
ni
ni
yu
yu
ku
ku
no
no
sa
sa
and
und
set
zie
out
hen
in
hi
se
naus,
ar
um
ch
auf
of
Schatz
so
su
me
che
th
zu
ing
ONE
to
ge
ONE
PIECE
fi
hen:
PIECE
ONE
ONE
PIECE
Co
Ein
Ra
Ra
mp
Kom
shin
shin
as
pass
ba
ba
ses
hält
n
n
on
im
nan
nan
ly
Grun
te
te
ca
de
use
nur
juu
juu
del
auf.
tai
tai
ays
no
no
Ra
Ra
mo
mo
to
to
shin
shin
ba
ba
n
n
nan
nan
te
juu
juu
tai
tai
no
no
mo
mo
Co
Ein
mp
to
to
Kom
as
pass
ses
hält
on
im
ly
Grun
ca
de
use
nur
del
auf.
De
Mit
Ne
Ne
li
ho
tsu
tsu
ri
hem
ni
ni
ous
Fie
u
u
wi
ber
ka
ka
th
stell
sa
sa
fe
ich
re
re
ve
mich
r,
ans
ka
ka
I
Ruder.
Ne
Ne
ji
ji
ta
wo
wo
to
ke
ru
to
no
the
tsu
ru
sa
he
ni
no
u
tsu
ka
u
sa
sa
re
ka
ka
ji
ji
wo
wo
to
to
ru
ru
no
no
De
sa
sa
Mit
li
ho
ri
hem
ous
Fie
wi
ber
th
stell
fe
ich
ve
mich
r,
ans
I
Ruder.
If
Die
HO
HO
the
alte
KO
KO
du
Schatz
RI
RI
sty
kar
ka
ka
tr
te
bu
bu
ea
führt
tte
tte
su
zum
ta
ta
re
Ziel.
map
HO
ta
ka
HO
ra
has
no
ka
chi
be
zu
ra
KO
en
mo
no
RI
ve
ka
ri
bu
bu
tte
tte
ta
ka
ka
ra
ra
no
no
chi
chi
zu
zu
mo
mo
If
Die
the
alte
du
Wenn
sty
Ta
tr
Schatz
ea
Du
su
shi
re
kar
map
dir
has
ka
th
te
Ta
si
be
me
en
führt
shi
cher
it's
ta
ka
zum
ve
bist,
not
no
me
Ziel.
ri
ist
a
na
ta
es
fi
ra
le
kei
no
den
ed,
ne
ge
se
na
Le
nd!
tsu
ra
gen
den
ja
se
Ta
tsu
de!
ja
na
Ta
i!
na
shi
i!
ka
ka
me
me
ta
ta
no
no
na
ra
ra
den
den
se
se
tsu
tsu
ja
ja
na
na
i!
Wenn
th
Du
en
dir
it's
si
not
i!
a
cher
le
bist,
ge
ist
nd!
es
Wh
Und
Ko
Ko
en
ge
ji
ji
it
rät
n
n
co
man
te
te
mes
selbst
ki
ki
to
in
na
na
pe
ei
a
a
rs
nen
ra
ra
on
Sturm,
shi
shi
al
wa
wa
Ko
Ko
da
st
re
da
ka
or
no
re
ji
ji
n
te
te
ki
ki
na
na
a
a
ra
ra
shi
shi
wa
wa
da
da
re
re
ka
ka
Wh
no
en
Und
it
ge
co
rät
no
man
mes
selbst
to
in
pe
ei
rs
nen
on
Sturm,
al
kann
st
BA
or
man
ms,
I
si
sich
BA
O
mp
je
I
RI
ly
man
O
ZU
ri
des
RI
MU
de
Strö
ZU
no
ab
mung
MU
kka
oa
an
no
t
rd
BA
kka
ver
so
te
t
trau
BA
en.
me
I
's
O
RI
RI
ZU
ZU
MU
MU
no
no
kka
kka
t
t
te
te
si
kann
mp
man
ly
sich
ri
je
de
man
ab
des
oa
Strö
rd
mung
so
an
me
ver
one
Und
el
O
se
trau
's
so
bi
mo
or
en.
and
tun,
O
i
hy
als
pr
su
mo
wä
thm
go
et
re
i
se
end
nichts
su
ba
it
ge
go
ii!
is
we
se
O
n't
sen!
ba
mo
th
i
ii!
su
i
go
su
se
go
ba
se
ii!
ba
Und
ii!
so
and
tun,
pr
als
et
wä
end
re
it
nichts
is
ge
n't
we
th
sen!
We
Wir
A
A
're
fol
ri
ri
go
gen
tta
tta
ing
al
ke
ke
to
le
no
no
ga
un
yu
yu
th
se
me
me
er
ren
wo
wo
up
Träu
A
A
all
men.
ka
ka
our
ki
ki
ri
ri
a
dr
tta
a
tsu
ea
me
tta
ke
tsu
no
yu
yu
me
me
wo
wo
ka
ka
ki
ki
a
a
tsu
tsu
me
me
We
Wir
're
fol
go
gen
ing
al
to
le
ga
un
th
se
er
und
up
Sa
all
ren
our
zie
and
ga
Sa
Träu
dr
hen
set
shi
ga
men.
ea
hi
out
mo
shi
naus,
ms
no
in
um
mo
wo
se
auf
no
sa
ar
Schatz
wo
ga
ch
su
sa
shi
of
Sa
ga
che
so
ni
shi
zu
Sa
yu
me
ge
ni
ku
th
hen:
yu
no
ing
ga
ku
sa
to
shi
no
mo
shi
no
mo
wo
no
sa
sa
ga
ga
shi
ni
ni
yu
yu
ku
ku
no
no
sa
sa
and
und
set
zie
out
hen
in
hi
se
naus,
ar
um
ch
auf
of
Schatz
so
su
me
che
th
zu
ing
ge
to
hen:
fi
Willst
nd
PO
A
du
PO
KE
co
die
KE
TTO
in
Mün
TTO
no
no
ze
my
KO
KO
aus
po
IN
IN
mei
ck
ner
et,
Ta
PO
PO
KE
sche
TTO
KE
no
no
KO
KO
IN
IN
A
Willst
and
du
So
die
co
o
do
So
re
Mün
in
der
you
re
to
ze
in
lie
wa
to
You
aus
my
ber
nna
You
wan
mei
po
mein
be
wan
na
ner
ck
Freund
my
na
be
Ta
et,
sein?
fr
be
my
sche
ie
my
Friend?
Friend?
nd?
So
So
re
re
to
to
You
You
wan
wan
na
na
be
be
my
my
Friend?
and
o
do
der
you
lie
wa
ber
nna
mein
be
Freund
my
sein?
fr
We
ie
are,
nd?
are
We
on
are,
the
are
cruise!
on
We
are,
are,
are
are
on
on
the
the
cruise!
cruise!
We
We
are!
are!
You're the Rare Breed
Der Mann in der Kiste
Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode. Subtitles will likely not function properly. Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv: https://mpv.io
Der benutzte Mediaplayer unterstützt das in dieser Episode verwendete Untertitelformat nicht. Die Untertitel werden wahrscheinlich nicht korrekt angezeigt werden. Bitte verwende einen der empfohlenen Videoplayer, vorzugsweise mpv: https://mpv.io
You foolish pirates.
Närrische Piraten!
You dare attack the Going Merry, knowing that it is commandeered
Greift ihr sehenden Auges die unbesiegbare Flotte an,
{commanded by Captain Usopp-sama of the Going Merry?! - OG}by Captain Usopp and his invincible pirate fleet?!
die von Käpt’n Usopp auf seinem Schiff, der Going Merry, kommandiert wird?!
All hands on deck! Prepare for battle!
Zum Angriff, Männer! Angriff!
{C'mon, you guys. Show [/i1]some[/i0] interest in other people... - OG}{Come on, guys... Does it hurt that much to play along a bit? - arch}{[/q2]Come on, guys... Would it really hurt you to play along a bit? - Ravenfire}Come on, guys... Would it really hurt to play along a bit?
Kommt schon, Leute.
It's done!
Fertig!
Look! It's our pirate flag!
Schaut! Eine Piratenflagge!
{Now that Usopp's joined and we have four people, - OG}{We've got four crew members now, now that Usopp's joined! - arch}{We've got four crew members and all, now that Usopp's joined! - arch: Getting rid of the "now" repetition}We've got four crew members now that Usopp's joined!
Da wir mit Usopp jetzt zu viert sind,
It's time we had our own Jolly Roger!
brauchen wir unsere eigene Flagge!
{Is that... supposed to be our emblem? - arch}{Is that... supposed to be our symbol? - Ravenfire}Is that... supposed to be our Jolly Roger?
Das soll unsere Flagge sein?
How is it? Cool, right?
Was meint ihr? Toll, was?
{A pirate flag is a symbol of death. A symbol of fear! - OG}A pirate flag is supposed to be scary, a symbol of death.
Eine Piratenflagge braucht einen Totenschädel.
{[/q2]I do feel scared, though scared to see any more of your artwork. - arch}I do feel scared, though scared of your artwork.
Ein Zeichen des Schreckens ist das.
You should have just said something.
Hättet ihr mir nur mal gleich was gesagt.
Don't forget that I'm famous for my artistic talent.
Denn mit mir habt ihr einen talentierten Künstler an Bord!
Artistic talent?
Einen was?
When it comes to painting,
Ich bemale nun schon seit 50 Jahren Hauswände!
{When it comes to painting, I'm in a league all my own! - OG}{nobody can beat my fifty years of experience in graffitiing walls. - arch; Kinda cumbersome but fits the CPS better; 18 CPS}no one can top the fifty years I spent graffitiing on walls.{Ravenfire; if experience is meant to focus on gaining a skill, you could swap "spent" for "studied" or "learned" and be at 16 CPS}
Wenn es um Bilder geht, bin ich euer Mann!
Wow! Fifty years?!
Wahnsinn! 50 Jahre?!
Now, gaze upon my artistic masterpiece!
Gut. Dann schaut euch dieses Meisterwerk an!
Ta-da!
Tadaa!
{Who said you should design it after yourself? - arch; 18 CPS}Who said to make it look like you?
Du solltest aber nicht deine Flagge malen.
Maybe something like this?
Das sollte aber passen.
Wow, that's pretty good!
Wow, das ist echt nicht schlecht.
Yeah, it looks great. I love it!
Ja. Richtig gut. Gefällt mir.
So this will be our symbol?
Das ist nun unsere Flagge!
{Alright! Usopp! Draw one on the sail, too! - OG}{Alright, Usopp! Now draw the same one on the sail! - arch}Alright, Usopp! Let's draw it on the sail too!
Gut. Usopp, mal auch noch eins auf die Segel.
You got it!
Geht klar.
Alright! All done!
Okay, passt alles!
{And with this, our pirate ship, [/i1]Going Merry[/i0], is finally complete! - arch}{This finally completes our pirate ship, [/i1]Going Merry[/i0]! - Ravenfire}Our pirate ship, the Going Merry, is finally ready!
Nun ist unsere Going Merry ein echtes Piratenschiff!
Phew! I'm exhausted!
Ich bin erledigt...
{Is this the right way? It seems kinda dangerous... - OG}Should we really go this way? That looks like trouble.
Stimmt die Richtung?
Trouble?
Was?!
Hold on.
Moment!
That must be it...
Das ist es.
{That's the place! No doubt about it! - OG}It is! No doubt about it!
Das ist der Ort. Ohne Zweifel.
Did you see something interesting?
Siehst du da irgendwas Spannendes?
The legendary treasure island.
Die legendäre Schatzinsel!
{The legendary Treasure Island? I've heard of that before! - OG}{"Legendary treasure island"? I've heard about that once! - arch}"Legendary treasure island"? I've heard about it!
Die legendäre Schatzinsel?
{Yeah! It's a famous island among pirates! - OG}That's right. This island is famous among pirates.
Jo, unter Piraten ist die richtig berühmt.
{There's all sorts of rumors about it. - arch: She does literally say "strange rumors" and I'd love to preserve it, but it's hard to fit into the CPS}Many odd rumors surround it.{Ravenfire; could also swap "surround" with "emerge from" if you got rid of that for a reason}
Gibt auch ziemlich makabere Geschichten...
Odd rumors?
Makabere Geschichten?
{That whoever gets near the island incurs a god's wrath... - OG}{Like, "Whoever comes near this island will feel the anger of the gods." - arch}Like, "Whoever comes near this island will feel the wrath of the gods."
Dass jeder, der Fuß auf die Insel setzt,
{W-Were the rumors really true?! Is this the god's wrath?! - OG}{Does this mean the rumors are true? Is this the anger of the gods?! - arch}So the rumors are true? Is this the wrath of the gods?!
U-Und die Gerüchte stimmen? Uns trifft der Zorn Gottes?!
Whatever it is, it sounds fun!
Klingt ziemlich witzig!
Luffy, you don't mean...
Luffy, wir wollen doch nicht etwa...
He does!
Doch, genau das wollen wir!
Let's go to the treasure island!
Gehen wir auf Schatzsuche!
Man, I'm hungry.
Ich hab Hunger.
I'll just sleep.
Ich leg mich hin.
{I'm amazed he can sleep in a place as creepy as this. - arch}{I'm amazed he can take a nap in a place as creepy as this. - Ravenfire}I'm amazed he can nap in such a creepy place.
Wie kann der an so einem Ort schlafen?
{Yeah. What kind of nerves does he have? - OG}{I wonder if there's [/i1]anything[/i0] that fazes him. - arch}Just what are his nerves made of?
Jo, der hat Nerven aus Stahl.
What?! Don't scare me like that!
Was treibst du da? Du machst mir Angst.
{N-No, I just thought I'd do a little dance to liven things up! - OG}Ah... you see... I just thought I'd dance a little to cheer us up a bit!
N-Nein, ich mach nur einen Tanz, um uns Mut zu machen.
You see? Like this, see?
Da? Da? Da?
Cut that out, Luffy...
Hör auf damit, Luffy!
Th-This...
W-Was ist das?
Leave this place.
Verlasst diesen Ort...
Who's that?!
Wer ist da?
Leave this place!
Verlasst diesen Ort!
Where's that voice coming from?
Von wo kommt die Stimme?
I am the guardian deity of this island.
Ich bin der Schutzgott dieser Insel.
Begone from this place at once if you value your lives!
Verlasst die Insel, wenn euch euer Leben lieb ist!
Guardian deity?
Ein Schutzgott?
You people are pirates, right?
Ihr seid doch Piraten, oder?
Yup.
Jo.
{Ravenfire note: Both official and fan manga translations I looked at repeat this phrase with similar wording to 6:44. Maybe we should too? Kind of like he's second guessing himself and then confirming it. The current translation sounds more confident.}{The written sentence can sound that way, but his tone of voice here has more of this "As I feared/suspected" feel. I don't think there's a *need* to repeat the phrasing of 6:44, but if you find some sentence like "Pirates, huh? I feared as much." that comes off a bit more naturally we can go with that. -arch}Pirates, huh? Thought so.
Piraten, hatte ich es mir gedacht.
Why would a deity ask such a thing?
Warum würde ein Gott so etwas fragen?
{Listen! Just try taking another step into the forest! - OG}Listen closely. The moment you step into this forest,
Hört! Wagt nur, einen weiteren Schritt in den Wald zu setzen.
{The instant you do, will you receive my divine punishment and meet your doom?! - OG}you will suffer the gods' judgment and face certain doom, won't you?
Aber dann wird euch die göttliche Strafe widerfahren.
{How should I know? Why are you asking me? - OG}How should I know? Why are you asking me?
Weiß ich doch nicht. Was fragste das?
Just what is going on?
Was hat der denn?
This guy is kinda weird.
Komischer Vogel.
What did you say, straw hat boy?!
Was hast du gesagt, Junge mit Strohhut?
What's with this place?
W-Was ist das denn?
{Humans I completely transformed when they came to look for treasure. - OG}{This is what's left of the humansthat came here looking for treasure. - This line is tough. Lit. it's "*I* completely transformed all the humans that came looking for treasure", with no explicit reference to what's shown on screen. - arch}This is what I did to the humans that came here looking for treasure.
Menschen, die ich verwandelt habe, weil sie nach dem Schatz suchten.
So that means you really are a god?!
Dann bist du wirklich ein Gott?!
A lot of these look really strange.
Schau dir die komischen Viecher an...
Is this one a lion?
Ist das ein Löwe?
Isn't it a pig?
Eher ein Schwein?
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Au, au, autsch.
Wh-What in the world are you?!
W-Was bist du denn für einer?
{I'm a rubber person! I ate a Devil Fruit! - OG}I'm a rubber man! I ate a devil fruit.
Ich bin ein Gummimensch. Hab ’ne Teufelsfrucht gegessen.
A devil fruit? That's absurd!
Eine Teufelsfrucht? Nun erzähl mir keine Märchen.
{I heard rumors about them long ago when I used to be a pirate, but... - OG}I heard about those back when I was a pirate, but
Ich hab Gerüchte davon gehört, als ich noch Pirat war, aber...
"Back when I was a pirate"?
Du warst mal ein Pirat?
{N-No! I'm not reminiscing about old times at all! - OG}{[/q2]N-No! I don't have any happy memories of that time or anything! - arch}N-No! It's not like I often reminisce on those times or anything!
N-Nein! Und nostalgisch bin ich da auch kein bisschen!
{You know, just leave me out of thistalk about old times! - arch, Lit: "Really, I don't want to hear about the past!"}You know, let's stop digging up the past!
Ich will echt keine alten Geschichten auspacken!
{What're you talking about? You're the one who said it! - OG}{What are you on about? [/i1]You[/i0] brought this up. - arch - Somehow this doesn't feel like Luffy, but it's the best I could find}What're you saying? You brought this up.
Was willst du? Du hast doch damit angefangen.
Are you really a god?
Bist du wirklich ein Gott?
{Shut up! If you won't leave, then receive my divine punishment! - OG}{[/i1]Silence! If you refuse to leave, then suffer the gods' judgement! - arch}Silence! Leave now or suffer the judgment of the gods!
Seid ruhig! Wenn ihr nicht verschwindet, ereilt euch die göttliche Strafe!
Not bad, god guy.
Jetzt haste es geschafft, Onkel Gott.
H-How are you still standing?
W-Wie kannst du noch stehen?
Oh, he's over there?
Da steckst du!
Don't move!
Keine Bewegung!
I said don't move!
Du sollst dich nicht bewegen!
Wh... What?! No fair!
Gibt’s doch nicht!
You know, god, or whatever you are...
Hey, Gott oder was auch immer...
you can't hurt this guy, even with a pistol.
Pistolen wirken bei dem Jungen nicht.
Still, don't startle me like that.
Aber die hat mich erschreckt, das mag ich nicht.
I-It's a monster!
M-Monster!
Hey! There he is!
D-Da!
It was just a pistol after all.
Da ist sie. Seine Pistole.
Where'd he go?
Wo ist er hin?
What's this?
Was ist das?
Is this... the guardian deity?
Ist das dieser Gott?
It moved!
Es bewegt sich!
{Stand me up, already! I said stand me up! - OG}{What are you waiting for?! Stand me back up! - arch}What are you waiting for?! Lift me back up!
Nun helft mir schon auf. Macht schon!
It's a human.
Das ist ein Mensch!
That's so funny! Is he a sponge?{arch - This is "tawashi", a sponge or scrubbing brush. It also becomes Luffy's nickname for Gaimon later. I went with "sponge guy" because of this, but I also saw other TLs go with "shrub guy" - both would work.}
Witzig. Wie eine Scheuerbürste!
{What's so god-like about [/i1]you[/i0]?! You thought you could trick us! - OG}{[/q2]You little...[/i1]You're[/i0] supposed to be a god? What a bunch of cheap tricks. - arch}You little... What kind of god relies on cheap tricks?
Was ist an dir schon göttlich? Wolltest uns wohl reinlegen?
Just shut it and stand me back up!
Schweige still! Und helft mir endlich auf!
{Don't boss us around after falling over! - arch: ever-so-slight cps improvement; 19 CPS}So bossy after you fell!
Tön nicht so, nachdem du umgekippt bist.
Alright, that should do it.
So, das sollte reichen.
Gaimon Inhabitant of the Island
Gaimon Inselbewohner
You're pretty popular here, god guy.
Bist ja reichlich beliebt, du Gott.
So you've been using these animals to drive any intruders off the island.
Du hast die Viecher also dazu benutzt,
{But I've never seen a person stuffed inside a treasure chest before! - OG}{But you know, I've never seen a guy living in a treasure chest before. - arch; 17 CPS}But, um, I've never seen a guy living in a treasure chest before.
Aber ich hab noch nie gesehen, dass ein Mensch in einer Schatztruhe hockt.
{Did your parents treasure you that much? - arch, 17 CPS}{arch note: A bit of a rewrite to make the joke land. He's literally asking "are you a 'son-in-a-box'", which is a pun on the expression /'daughter-in-a-box' for a girl who grows up sheltered from the world. Open to other pun ideas.}Did your family treasure you that much?
Sozusagen ein goldener Käfig?
{Yeah. I've been overly pampered since I was just a little boy... - OG}Yes. Ever since I was a child, they'd express their love for me by...
Ja. Meine Eltern haben mich schon immer gut behütet...
As if!
Natürlich nicht!
{I can't get out of this box! I'm stuck! - arch}I can't get out of this box! I'm trapped!
Ich komm nicht aus der Truhe raus!
{I've been alone on this island and in this box for 20 years now! - OG}I've been on this island for twenty years all alone and stuck in this chest!
Seit 20 Jahren bin ich ganz allein auf der Insel
Twenty years?!
20 Jahre?!
{You've been all alone on this island for 20 years? - OG}{You've been all alone here for twenty years? - arch}You've been here by yourself for twenty years?
Du bist seit 20 Jahren allein hier auf der Insel?
{My hair and mustache are just as you can see. Even my eyebrows got connected... - OG}Just look at my hair and my beard. Even my eyebrows have connected.
So ist mir auch das Haar und der Bart gewachsen.
{It's also been 20 years since I've conversed with anyone like this. - OG}{This is my first time in twenty years talking to other people. - arch}{I haven't spoken to anyone in two decades! - arch/Z}{This is my first conversation with anybody in twenty years! - arch}This is my first conversation with anybody in two decades.
Es ist 20 Jahre her, dass ich mal so normal mit jemandem gesprochen habe.
Do you understand how lonely it's been?
Wisst ihr überhaupt, wie schmerzhaft das ist?
Sounds dumb.
Klingt albern.
What did you say?!
Was willst du?!
Oh, so that's where you were.
Ah, da seid ihr...
{You were asleep this whole time, even after all that happened?! - OG}{You want to tell us you've just been sleeping through all this ruckus? - arch; 17 CPS}{You're telling us you've just been sleeping through all this ruckus? - arch: slight cps improvement; 17 CPS}{You're telling us you just slept through all that commotion? - Ravenfire}You're telling us you slept through all that commotion?
Hast du die ganze Zeit geschlafen, obwohl so viel los war?
Huh?! What the hell is that?!
W-Wer ist denn der Knilch?!
Now you notice?
Bist mal wieder ein Blitzmerker.
He's a guy stuck in a treasure chest.
Der Kerl hockt in einer Schatztruhe!
What?! His parents treasured him that much?!
Also sozusagen ein goldener Käfig?
{Yeah. I've been overly pampered since I was just a little boy... - OG}Yes. Ever since I was a child, they'd express their love for me by...
Ja, meine Eltern haben mich schon immer gut behütet...
As if!
Natürlich nicht!
It wasn't funny the first time!
Und macht denselben blöden Witz nicht zweimal!
Zoro, gimme a hand.
Zoro, hilf mir mal eben.
{Ow! Ow! What do you think you're doing?! - arch}Ow! Ow! What are you doing?!
Au! Au! Was macht ihr denn da?
Stop it! You'll rip my head off!
Hört auf! Ihr reißt mir ja den Kopf ab!
Whew... He really can't get out!
Hattest recht. Du kannst da nicht raus.
What did you expect?!
Was soll man machen?
{Because of my lack of exercise over the years, this treasure chest fits together with my body now! - OG}I haven't gotten any exercise in years. My body barely even fits in this box.
Ich hab mich die letzten Jahre auch nur entsprechend bewegen können.
{If you try to break it, my body'll get destroyed, too! - OG}{If you broke the box, my body might just break down! - arch}In fact, this box is the only thing holding me together!
Wenn du sie kaputtmachst, ist mein Körper auch dahin.
He sure talks a lot.
Ziemlich dumme Kiste.
{Anyway, what's up with the lot of you? - arch}Anyway, what's the story behind your little crew?
Wer seid ihr überhaupt?
{You're [/i1]nothing[/i0] like any of the other pirates who've come here. - OG}{You're nothing at all like all the other pirates that came here. - arch}You're nothing at all like the other pirates that came here.
Ihr seid nicht wie die anderen Piraten, die vor euch hier waren.
{I'm Luffy! I'm gonna become the Pirate King and find the One Piece! - arch}{I'm Luffy! I'm gonna become the Pirate King and find One Piece! - Ravenfire}I'm Luffy! I'm gonna be the Pirate King and find the One Piece!
Ich bin Luffy. Ich werde Piratenkönig und finde das One Piece.
The One Piece?!
Das One Piece?!
{Don't tell me you're seriously planning to enter the Grand Line?! - OG}{You don't mean you want to enter the Grand Line? - arch}{You mean you want to enter the Grand Line? - arch/muffinman}You don't actually mean to enter the Grand Line, do you?!
Ihr wollt doch nicht allen Ernstes auf die Grand Line ziehen?
I have a map to get there and all!
Wir haben schon eine Karte der Grand Line.
Don't underestimate that place!
Unterschätzt das mal nicht.
{It's like a graveyard in the middle of hell! - arch - Lit. "graveyard and hell"}{It's like a graveyard within a nightmare! - Ravenfire; I assume hell counts as a real world reference so hopefully this is a close alternative}{Hmm. I'm fine with the rewrite, but he does say  (=hell) here. Not necessarily the hell belonging to some specific religion, but the general concept. I've been thinking for a while about whether it might be good to loosen that rule on "hell" in particular, especially if they themselves say it in Japanese.}It'll cause you hell or be your death!
Das ist die Hölle dort! Oder eher ein Friedhof.
{I once saw pirates who'd managed to escape from the Grand Line! - OG}A long time ago, I saw a crew of pirates return from the Grand Line.
Ich hab Piraten gesehen, die von der Grand Line entkommen konnten.
{They looked almost like people who had died and lost their souls! - OG}{They looked like dead men, as if they had lost their souls. - arch}{They looked like dead men who had lost their souls. - Ravenfire}They looked like walking corpses, utterly soulless.
Sie sahen aus wie Tote, die ihre Seelen verloren hatten.
{Something incredibly horrific must've happened, or they must've run into monsters or something...- OG}{I don't know what they experienced, but it must have been terrifying. - arch - Lit: "Whether they experienced something terrifying, or ran into monsters... [I can't say]"}But whatever they had encountered, it must have been terrifying.
Sie müssen die schlimmsten Dinge erlebt haben...
{Not a single one of them spoke even a word. - Ravenfire}None of them spoke a single word.
Keiner von ihnen wollte auch nur darüber reden.
{On top of that, rumors about the One Piece spawn even more rumors, - OG}That aside, with so many rumors surrounding the One Piece,
Und die Gerüchte über das One Piece wurden auch immer ausgeschmückter.
{nobody can tell if any of them are even true. - arch}{nobody can tell if any of them are really true. - Ravenfire}there's no way of knowing what to believe.
Wer weiß schon, was da noch wahr und was falsch dran ist.
{Some 20-odd years since the start of the Great Pirate Era, - OG}{It's been over twenty years since the Great Pirate Era began. - arch}It's been over two decades since the dawn of the Great Pirate Era.
Es ist über 20 Jahre her, dass das große Piratenzeitalter begonnen hat.
{the One Piece is already a dream within a dream beyond a legend! - OG}{At this point, the One Piece is beyond legend. A dream in a dream. - arch}{And now, One Piece is beyond legend, a dream within a dream. - Ravenfire}And now, the One Piece is beyond legend, a dream within a dream.
Das One Piece ist zu einem entfernten Traum in einer Legende geworden.
{Then, where on that is the Grand Line? - arch}So, where on there is the Grand Line?
Was da ist nun die Grand Line?
{Dunno. Don't [/i1]you[/i0] know, old scrub brush guy? - OG}No idea... You don't know, sponge guy?
Keine Ahnung, weißt du’s nicht, Scheuerbürstenmann?
{I have no idea how to read these charts. - arch}These sea charts don't mean a thing to me.
Ich kann keine Seekarte lesen.
Yeah. Same here.
Ah, da haben wir was gemeinsam!
You're really not acting like a pirate here.{You're not acting like much of a pirate. - Ravenfire}
Das ist kein Gespräch zwischen Piraten!
In any case, even if you entered the Grand Line,
Aber wenn wir wirklich auf die Grand Line segeln,
{earning as much money as we can, then escaping, is the best idea. - OG}{it'd be best to just grab all treasure you can get and bounce. - arch}it'd be best to just grab as much treasure as possible and bounce.
sollten wir uns einfach möglichst viel Geld schnappen und wieder verschwinden.
{I will find the One Piece! I have good luck! - OG}{Oh, I'll find the One Piece. I'm a lucky guy. - arch}Oh, I'll find the One Piece. I'm pretty lucky.
Ich finde das One Piece. Ich bin ein Glückspilz.
{I wonder where you get that confidence from. - arch: I wanna go for "keep wondering" or "always wonder" but it doesn't fit the CPS}{Ravenfire note: I probably like OG better but throwing this out in case it generates any more ideas: "I keep wondering how you [stay]/[got] so confident."}I wonder how you stay so confident.
Wo nimmst du eigentlich das Selbstvertrauen her?
Just watch, I'll find it for sure!
Ich krieg das schon hin. Wart’s nur ab.
Oh, dear...
Wenn du das sagst...
That look...
So ähnlich...
{Your face looks just like mine. It's like we were twins. - arch}{Your face is just like mine was. It's as if we were twins. - Ravenfire}Your face is just like mine was. It's as if we're twins.
Du bist wie ich. Du siehst mir sogar ähnlich, wir könnten Zwillinge sein.
Have you seen yourself recently?
Der sieht dir nicht mal annähernd ähnlich!
I understand how you feel.
Ich verstehe das.
{One day, our dream would be in our hands. - arch: ugh, I kinda hate it, but CPS doesn't allow much more.}{One day, our dream would be in our reach. - Ravenfire}One day, we would reach our dreams.
Man möchte sich seine Träume realisieren.
That's what we always believed!
So haben wir auch einmal gedacht!
"We"?
Wir?
{We were willing to put our lives on the line to search for treasure! - OG}{We'd happily put our lives on the line to search for treasure. - arch}We'd happily put our lives on the line in search of treasure.
Wir würden unser Leben bei der Schatzsuche riskieren!
That burning passion turned my life upside-down.
Jener Eifer hat damals mein ganzes Leben verändert.
H-Hold on, just what
M-Moment mal. Von was redest du?
It all started twenty years ago.
Vor 20 Jahren...
{Me and my pirate crewmates struck land on this island... - arch}{My pirate crewmates and I struck land on this island... - Ravenfire}My pirate crewmates and I made landfall on this island.
Da sind meine Piratenkumpels und ich auf diese Insel gekommen.
{to search for the treasure that was said to lie hidden here. - arch}We were searching for the treasure that was said to lie hidden here.
Wir wollten den Schatz finden, der hier liegen sollte.
{200 men have searched for a month now, but it's no use! - OG}All 200 of us have been searching this island for a full month now...
200 Mann haben einen Monat nach ihm gesucht, aber ohne Erfolg.
{All we've found on this island is this one empty treasure chest! - OG}but this empty chest was the only thing we found!
Wir fanden lediglich diese leere Schatztruhe.
Men, get ready to leave!
Wir ziehen ab!
{What're you doing, Gaimon? We're going on ahead! - OG}What are you waiting for, Gaimon? We're leaving.
Was hast du, Gaimon? Wir machen ’n Abflug!
Gaimon (Twenty Years Ago)
Gaimon (vor 20 Jahren)
Right.
Ja.
I wonder if anybody ever searched up there.
Hat denn da oben jemand nachgeschaut?
{[/q2]It's right where the captain stayed the whole month, but... - arch}The captain stayed around here the whole month, but...{Ravenfire; The OG makes it sound like the captain stayed atop the hill the whole month but then Gaimon wouldn't need to search it. Or is the intent that he stayed on top of the hill?}
Der Käpt’n blieb den ganzen Monat immer hier unten.
let's make sure one last time.{Ravenfire: can we swap "one last time" with "just to be safe"? For the same reason as last line. One last time makes it sound like someone did check}{arch: He does say  here, which is "one last time". I'm guessing he's thinking "maybe they did check up there, just not hard enough".}
Ich schau noch mal schnell nach.
I couldn't believe my own eyes.
Ich konnte meinen Augen nicht trauen.
I... I found it! That's where it was!
I-Ich hab ihn gefunden. Er ist hier oben!
Hey! Everyone!
Hey! Jungs!
That was the moment I got stuck in this box.
Und da steckte ich plötzlich in der Kiste.
{When I came to, my crew was already far out to sea. - OG}When I came to, my crewmates were long gone.
Als ich wieder zu mir kam, waren meine Kameraden bereits in See gestochen.
Ahh! I messed up!
So ein Käse!
Wait.
Moment mal.
{Doesn't this mean that the treasure belongs to me alone now? - arch}Doesn't this mean that the treasure is all mine now?
Das heißt doch, dass das ganze Vermögen nun mir gehört.
Argh! I can't climb up like this!
Aber so kann ich da nicht hochklettern!
I can't get out! I'm stuck, dammit!
Ich komm nicht raus. Ich komm nicht raus!
Hey! Come back!
Hey! Kommt zurück!
Ever since that day,
Und auch nach all den Jahren
{the fortune I only saw for an instant has never left my mind. - OG}I couldn't get my mind off that treasure for even a second.
denke ich noch immer an diesen Schatz, den ich so kurz erblicken durfte.
{Pirates have come to this island in search of treasure countless times, - OG}{Countless pirates came to this island looking for treasure, - arch}Countless pirates came to this island looking for riches,
Unzählige Piraten kamen auf die Insel, um ihn zu suchen.
but I scared them all off with the help of my animal friends.{but my animal friends helped me scare them all away. - Ravenfire}{Even if it's 16 CPS I'd like to revert this for now. The rewrite sounds to me like it was the "idea" of the animals to scare them away, but the point of the line is that Gaimon doesn't want to let anyone else near the treasure.}
Mit den Jungs hier habe ich sie alle verscheucht.
For twenty years, I've protected the treasure this way.
So habe ich den Schatz dieser Insel über 20 Jahre hinweg beschützt.
It belongs to me!
Er gehört mir!
{Yes, no doubt about it. That treasure is yours. - arch}Yup, no doubt about it. That treasure is yours.
Ja. Ohne Zweifel. Das ist deiner.
{Don't worry, Gaimon-[/i1]san[/i0]. - arch - In reality she says "I understand [what we need to do/what you want us to do]" here, but I can't make that work well}Leave it to us, Gaimon.
Also schön, Gaimon.
We'll get that treasure for you.
Wir holen den Schatz für dich.
R-Really?!
Wirklich?
Yeah.
Jupp.
Is she...
Du willst doch nicht...
{You're a thief who steals from pirates, right? - arch}Aren't you a thief who steals from pirates?
Bist du nicht ein Dieb, der nur von Piraten stiehlt?
Don't be rude!
Das ist unhöflich.
I do have some integrity, you know.
Selbst ich weiß, was sich gehört und was nicht.
This is it, huh?
Hier?
It's been a while since I've been here, too.
Ich war selbst schon lange nicht mehr hier.
{The time has finally come! Today is a great day! - OG}{So the time has finally come. Today is a great day. - arch}So it's finally time. Today is a great day.
Endlich ist es so weit. Was für ein herrlicher Tag.
{I'm counting on you, Straw Hat. - arch; This is too literal for my taste, but oh well. Really, it's something like "if you would", but less formal.}{That's your cue, Straw Hat. - Ravenfire; This could work. Maybe even "It's up to you now"}It's up to you now, Straw Hat.
Ich zähle auf dich, Strohhut.
Alright!
Also gut!
Gum-Gum...
Gum-Gum...
Rocket!
Rocket!
Woo-hoo!
Jawoll!
And? Is it there?
Und? Ist er da oben?!
It is! Five treasure chests!
Ich hab sie. Sechs Schatztruhen.
I-I did it!
G-Gut gemacht!
{I finally got it! The treasure! The treasure! - OG}I finally got my treasure! I got it!
Endlich habe ich ihn! Den Schatz, den Schatz!
Can you throw it down here?
Schmeiß den Schatz runter!
Throw me my treasure! Hurry up!
Mach schon, mach schon!
I don't wanna.
Nein!
What?!
Was?!
I don't wanna give it to you.
Nein. Ich schmeiß ihn nicht runter.
{What nonsense is this?! Quit joking around! - OG}What are you saying? Stop those stupid jokes!
Was soll das denn jetzt? Mach keinen Scheiß!
Cut it out, Luffy!
Hör mit den Albernheiten auf!
Don't worry about it.
Es soll mir recht sein.
{I don't mind. - arch: This is a second "It's alright", but this might flow better into the next lines}It's alright.
Es ist ja doch egal.
It's not alright!
Das ist es nicht.
{[/q2]Yeah, this is the treasure you've been protecting for twenty years! - arch}Yeah, this is the treasure you've been guarding for twenty years!
Eben! Du hast den Schatz für 20 Jahre beschützt, Gaimon.
Straw Hat, you're...
Strohhut. Du...
you're a great guy.
bist ein toller Knabe.
What do you mean?
Wie kommst du darauf?
{I've always had this slight fear in the back of my mind. - arch: More closely it's "I've always had this 'weak' thought 'what if...'". I'd love to get closer to that if there's something that works well.}{I've always trembled at the thought that what if... - Ravenfire}{I've always trembled at the thought of what if... - arch/Z}I've always had this slight suspicion in the back of my mind.
Ich hatte ja schon so eine Ahnung, dass das der Fall sein könnte...
{I just tried my best not to think about it. - arch}But I've tried my best not to think about it.
Ich hab den Gedanken immer weggeschoben, aber...
They're empty, aren't they?
Sie sind leer, nicht wahr?
Yeah. All of them.
Jo. Alle leer.
{It happens all the time with treasures that have treasure maps... - OG}{It's very common for treasures with maps to them. - arch}{It happens all the time for treasures with maps leading to them. - arch}It happens all the time when treasures have maps leading to them.
Das passiert häufig mit Schätzen, zu denen eine Schatzkarte führt...
{You search for it, only to find it already taken. - arch}{You follow the map, only to find the treasure already taken. - arch}You follow the map, but the loot's already gone.
Man geht nachschauen, aber es hat ihn schon jemand anderes gefunden.
{That's how much of an ordeal treasure-hunting is for pirates. - OG}That's what makes treasure hunting so brutal for pirates.
Diese Schatzsuche ist echt eine undankbare Aufgabe für Piraten.
{You can wait all your life, or lose your life, and never touch treasure... - OG}{You might spend a lifetime searching and still not reach it. - arch: Lit. it goes farther with "Wait for a lifetime or even die [on the way], and..."}You could spend a lifetime searching and still not reach it.
Man widmet dem sein ganzes Leben oder verliert es sogar
{There are more pirates like that than you can count! - OG}Countless pirates have suffered that fate.{Numerous pirates have suffered that fate. - Ravenfire; variation from 15:06}{I'd like this one to be Countless if possible, since he uses a pretty strong word in Japanese. If you really don't want the repetition, we can change up 15:06 instead.}
Von der Sorte gibt es mehr Piraten, als man zählen könnte.
Well, look on the bright side, sponge guy.
Nun heul nicht rum, Alterchen.
You're lucky we came here after twenty years.
Ist doch gut, dass wir nach 20 Jahren gekommen sind.
{If you had to wait another thirty, you could have died. - arch}If you had to wait another thirty, you could've died.
Noch mal 30 Jahre und du wärst wohl tot gewesen.
Straw Hat...
Strohhut...
Luffy...
Luffy...
He's...
Er...
After an embarrassment like this,
Stehst nun ordentlich dumm da.
{there's no harm in going right after the One Piece. - arch}there's no harm in going for the One Piece.
Jetzt gibt es nur noch das One Piece.
Come with us and be a pirate again!
Komm mit uns und sei wieder ein Pirat!
You'd really invite me?
Du lädst mich in deine Mannschaft ein?
Up until now,
Niemand, der mich je so gesehen hat,
{to talk to me before when they saw me like this! - OG}{nobody who looked at me even wanted to talk to me. - arch}{no one who gave me a second glance even wanted to talk to me. - Ravenfire}no one gave me a second glance, let alone talked to me.
wollte überhaupt nur ein Wort mit mir reden.
{It's been so long since I had somebody I could trust. - arch}How long has it been since I could trust somebody?
Wie lange ist es nun her, dass ich jemandem vertraut habe?
Thank you.
Ich danke dir...
You're really staying on this island, sponge guy?
Du willst wirklich auf der Insel bleiben, Alterchen?
Yeah, Straw Hat.
Ja, Strohhut.
{Even if there's no treasure here, there's more I want to protect. - arch}Even if the treasure's not here, there's something else I want to protect.
Auch wenn es hier keinen Schatz gibt, habe ich doch etwas zu beschützen.
Huh?
Ach?
Something else?
Was denn?
{I've shared hard times and happy times with these guys for 20 years. - OG}{I've lived with them for twenty years. We've been through a lot together. - arch; note: Lit. Through good and bad - I'm sure there's a great idiom for that but I just can't remember which.}I've lived with them through thick and thin for twenty years.
Ich hab 20 Jahre mit den Jungs hier alles Mögliche durchgestanden.
There's no way I'd abandon them.
Ich kann sie nicht einfach zurücklassen.
{Now that I know there's no treasure, I somehow finally feel free. - OG}{Now that I know there's no treasure, I finally feel like I can live freely. - arch}{Now that I know there's no treasure, I finally feel like I can be free. - Ravenfire; variation from live in next 2 lines}Now that I know there's no treasure, I finally feel like I'm free.
Und da ich nun weiß, dass es keinen Schatz gibt,
From now on, I can truly live my own life.
Jetzt kann ich das Leben leben, das ich schon immer wollte.
And you know, I've kind of grown to like living in a box.
Zumal mir die Truhe auch langsam auf die Eier geht.
I see. That's too bad. You're a cool guy.
Ah, schade. Bist ein witziger alter Kerl.
{So these strange animals are your real friends. - arch: 18 CPS but I can't find a way to make it shorter that still works with the joke in the next line.}So these weird animals are your real friends.
Die komischen Viecher sind also deine Kameraden.
{Well, you're the strangest animal of them all. - arch}But you're the weirdest animal of them all.
Er ist doch das komischste Vieh von allen.
What?!
Bitte was?!
Bye, bye! Take care!
Bis dann. Halt die Ohren steif.
Goodbye!
Macht’s gut!
Straw Hat...
Strohhut!
do your best to achieve your dreams. For my sake, too.
Verfolg deinen Traum. Tu es für mich.
I'm sure you can find it.
Wenn es jemand schaffen kann, dann du...
The legendary treasure, One Piece.
Finde den legendären Schatz, das One Piece!
{And with it, make the world your own! - arch: I'm... not sure what this is supposed to mean. Lit. it's "Buy the world", but I'm unsure what exactly he's implying. This TL should be a pretty safe one, though.}And then, make the world your own!
Und dann...